피격당했다
모두, 충격에 대비해!
(over radio): We've been hit!
Everybody, brace for impact!
제이크, 하나만 물어보도록 하지, 비밀로 했으면 하네.
Jake, I want to ask you something,
and it stays between us.
러시아인과 팔레스타인인의 관계에 대해 아는게 있나?
What do you know about
Russian-Palestinian relations?
세르게이 미쉬네프
VANCE:
Sergei Mishnev.
우리 정보에 의하면, 세르게이는 살아있습니다.
Our Intel says Sergei survived.
어떻게? 내가 쐈어
How? I hit him.
분명 쓰러졌어.
일어났겠죠.
He went down.
He got up.
뭐?
빨리~~
What?
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
(gunshot)
이제 시작일뿐이네, 친구
Only the beginning,
my friend.
둘에 대한 소문 들어봤지?
MAN: Well, you know the deal
with them two, don't you?
무슨 얘기요?
Them two who?
맥그라프 판사?
Judge McGraff?
그래, 윌슨 검사하고.
And Wilson, the D.A.
대학때부터 사겼다던데?
The two of them used to be
college sweethearts.
정말예요?
Is that a fact?
Check 'em out
법정가면, 잘봐봐. 둘이 아주 끈적끈적해
next time you're in court--
little looks
between 'em, smiles.
그가 이의제기하면, 그녀가 받아들여, 매번.
He objects, she sustains, every time.
The old flame's
아직 잊지 못한거네요, 그죠?
still burning, huh?
I think they'd burn it up
그 둘은 말야, 법정안에서도 뒹굴 수 있을걸?
right there on the bench
if they could.
키이스, 짖꿎긴..
Keyes, you are bad.
저놈만 하겠냐..
Not as bad as this yahoo.
(siren blaring)
갓길에 차 세워요
Pull over to the side, please.
(siren continues blaring)
(siren stops)
(indistinct radio chatter)
이 밤중에 뭐하십니까, 선생님?
How we doing tonight, sir?
면허증과 등록증 주세요
License and registration,
please.
(knocking on window)
그거 술병입니까?
What do we have there?
괜찮아요.
It's okay.
의사가 처방한 버번예요..
It's prescription bourbon.
(exhales)
♪ NCIS 12x15 ♪
Cabin Fever
Original Air Date on February 14, 2015
??NCIS 12x15 ??/font>
Cabin Fever
Original Air Date on February 14, 2015
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
깁스식 "말꼬리 잡기"와 토니 때문에 이번거는 정말 발자막입니다.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
?? ??
술에 대해 공평하게 말하면 말야,
You know,
all fairness to alcohol,
취하지 않았을 땐, 나도 그게 멍청한 짓이라 생각했어.
I've done stupid things
when I was sober, too.
농담할 기운은 있나보네.
I'm glad you think it's funny.
It's not.
알아. 딸 아이나, 내가 실망시킨 동료들에겐 농담이 아닐테지..
But it's nothing
I wanted my daughter
or anybody down at the Bureau to
make a big deal about, either.
그래서 날 부른건가?
So you called me?
자네한테라면, 변명하지 않아도 될줄 알았거든.
I figured I could count on you
for the shortest lecture.
버번이라고.. 투바이어스?
Bourbon... Tobias?
그래. 해결책을 겨우 찾아냈지.
Yeah. I barely
cracked it.
저녁식사때 반주로
It was mainly the beer
I had with dinner
맥주에 진통제 섞어 먹는거와 비슷한거야.
mixed with the pain medicine
I still take
뭔 소리 하려는지 알아..
for when you
shot me in the ass.
엄청 아프겠군...
It smarts like hell in cold weather.
No, no.
아니, 이봐, 경찰 보고서를 봤다구.
I saw the police report.
별일 아니야, 충분히 반성했고, 잊어버리겠네.
That was a fluke thing,
which I intend to learn from
and put behind me.
그러니, 자네도 내 친구라면, 그냥 넘어가주게
And if you were my friend,
you'd do the same thing.
(phone ringing)
레온?
Yeah, Leon?
그래.
Uh-kuh.
현장은?
Where?
뭔 일인데?
What's up?
도움이 필요하면 알려줘, 깁스
Let me know
if you need me, Gibbs.
빚 한번 졌네.
됐어.
I owe you one.
No, you don't!
(chuckles softly)
NCIS.
깁스.
Gibbs.
불은 꺼졌어요. 수사는 시작했고. 사관실에 있습니다.
Fire's out. Your team
just got here. Wardroom.
가스 폭발이라 생각하나?
그러길 바래야죠.
Are you still thinking gas explosion?
Well, I'm hoping.
주방은 하나고, 격리됐어요
Galley's one
compartment over.
오래된 가스랜지나 오븐이지 싶습니다
We're thinking maybe
a leaky stove or an oven.
이 사람들은 다 뭔가?
Who are
all these suits?
여러 국제기관 사람들이죠
Dignitaries from a dozen
international agencies.
발생당시 막 승선 중이였습니다
We'd just started boarding
when this happened.
많은 승무원들이 준비중이였구요
But there were
a bunch of crew members
in there setting up.
장관님은?
서해안으로 안전하게 모시고 있습니다
SECNAV?
On the West Coast-- we were
patching her in on closed circuit.
What's the occasion?
무슨 상황이지?
국제 테러경보가 발령됐어요
It's a summit
on global terror.
뻔한거군
No irony there.
안됩니다, 깁스
I'm not going there, Gibbs.
가스 누출이어야 한다구요
Keep thinking
gas leak.
(camera shutter clicks)
환영합니다, 보스
Welcome
to the party, boss.
희생자는?
Casualties.
아, 6명 확인됐는데, 2명은 함내병실에,
Uh, six reported injured,
two are in sick bay,
중환자 2명은 노포크 병원으로 후송중입니다.
two more seriously being
rushed to Norfolk Memorial.
그리고, 사망자 한명이네요
(sighs):
And one dead.
여자 하사관이고,
Female petty officer.
군번은 식별되지 않습니다.
Can't make out
her name tag.
박사님 부르겠습니다
I'll call Ducky.
가스 폭발이 아니군
네.
This is no gas explosion.
Yeah.
절대 아닙니다.
가스 냄새는 없고,
We had our doubts.
There's no smell of gas.
화약냄새 뿐이군.
이것도 있죠.
Just gunpowder.
TONY: And then there's this.
폭발물 파편?
Bomb fragment?
러시어어로.. 수류탄이라 써있군
It's in Russian--it says "grenade."
Just because
러시어어로 써졌다고, 꼭 그런 의미는...
it's in Russian
doesn't mean it's...
세르게이 미쉬노프
Sergei Mishnev.
그만둘리가 없죠, 깁스,
We knew he wasn't
done yet, Gibbs--
시간문제였습니다.
국장, 자네가 목표였단 거네.
just a matter of time.
This means you're the target.
당신 친구 모두가, 그놈의 적입니다.
Any friend of yours
is an enemy of his.
초대자 명단을 확인하죠
Let me check the guest list.
러시아 대사는 불참했고,
The Russian ambassador
had to cancel,
대신, 다른 사람을 보냈네요
우리가 아는 사람인가?
so they sent someone in his place.
Someone we know?
또 다른 친구죠.
Another friend.
밴스 국장님.
Director Vance.
깁스 요원님.
Agent Gibbs.
파블렌코 참사관님.
VANCE: Counselor Pavlenko.
Thank goodness
다들 무사해서 다행입니다.
you're all right.
방금 사고 소식을 들었어요
I just heard
about the explosion.
당신도 늦을 때가 있군요
Interesting
you being late.
다친 사람은요?
Was anyone hurt?
우리에게 무슨일이 일어난 겁니까?
Do we know what happened?
제 생각엔 말입니다.
We have a pretty good idea.
폭탄인가요?
러시아제 수류탄입니다.
A bomb?
A Russian grenade.
세르게이 라구요?
아닐까요?
You think Sergei?
You don't?
시미치 떼시는 것처럼 보입니다만..
And here you are conveniently
rolling in after the fact.
여러분, 제발, 이런 놀이는 그만둡시다
Gentlemen, please,
do not tell me
we're going to engage
in this farce yet again.
인정하시죠, 참사관님..
You have to admit, Counselor...
난 인정할 게 없어요
I admit nothing.
이거 하나만은 확실히 합시다, 국장.
In fact, let me
assure you, Director,
세르게이가 벌인 짓이라면,
if Sergei
목표는 나 요
is behind this,
I was his target.
당신도 아니고,
Not you.
깁스요원도 아니고. 나란말요.
Not Agent Gibbs. Me.
이런 범죄 때문에 날 또 의심하다니
PAVLENKO: I cannot believe I am forced
to defend myself once again
믿을 수가 없군요
for the actions of a criminal.
당신 동료였된 러시아인 짓입니다, 참사관님
A Russian criminal,
Counselor,
with whom you once had
a working relationship.
한번뿐이요, 국장.
그 실수의 댓가는
Once, Director.
And we have paid dearly
세르게이를 추방하는 것으로 충분히 치뤘소
for that mistake, leaving Sergei
now a man without a country.
피해자로 보이기 위한 댓가겠죠.
Freeing you up to
play the victim.
피해자가 아니오, 깁스, 나도 목표란 말입니다, 당신처럼.
Not a victim, Gibbs--
a target, like you.
그 이유 때문에 세르게이가 날 노리는 거고.
For reasons that make sense
only to Sergei.
어떤 이유말입니까?
Reasons such as?
헬기사고 말이요.
Your helicopter crash.
당신 구조에 도움을 준 걸, 그는 배신이라 생각해요
He saw my help in the rescue
as a betrayal.
도움요?
Help?
당신이 배신자들로부터 날 구했으니,
And now he perceives
이젠 내가 깁스요원에게
that I owe my life
to Agent Gibbs
목숨까지 빚졌다고 생각하겠죠..
for saving me from our
defector, the scientist.
당신이 넬리 베닌을 쐈기때문에,
You shoot Nelly Benin dead,
이젠 우리가 아주 친한 골프친구라 생각하는 거요
and now we're
practically golf buddies.
난 골프 안칩니다.
I don't golf.
그래요?.. 누군 같이 친답니까?
Well... who has time?
I mean, really.
깁스,
Gibbs,
부인 일에 대해선 깊은 조의를 표합니다.
my sympathy for your loss--
내게도 책임이 있다 생각해요
I have suffered a few myself--
근데, 우린 같은 배에 탔습니다.
but we are in this together.
아뇨, 그렇지 않습니다.
No, we're not.
죄송하지만, 참사관님, 당신이 이 괴물을 만든겁니다.
All due respect, Counselor,
you created this monster.
착각하지 마세요, 국장님
Don't fool yourself, Director.
많은 사람들이 한몫 했습니다.
Many hands went into
creating Sergei.
자, 이제, 내가 뭘 도와야 할지 말해주시죠
Now, please,
tell me what I can do.
이제 확실하게 된거죠, 깁스?
What can I say, Gibbs,
to convince you
내가 당신편이란게...
that I am on your side here?
좀 비켜주시죠.
You stay out of my way.
(distorted, echoing clicking
of camera shutter)
오, 가엽은 아이여.
Dear, a mere child.
그러게 말예요..
넓은 세상을 보고, 많은 경험을 하고,
Tell me about it.
Eager to serve, to learn,
배우고, 봉사하고 싶었으나,
to see the world and experience
its many adventures.
결국, 비겁한 폭탄때문에
Until along
comes a coward
홀로 남겨졌구나.
with a bomb.
보고해봐.
GIBBS: Update.
Where are we?
이 교활한 놈에게 신물이 난다네, 제스로
DUCKY: We are tired
of this insidious monster,
그건 확실하군.
순서를 지켜요, 덕.
Jethro, that's where we are.
Take a number, Duck.
맥기부터.
McGee.
남은 수류탄 파편을 모았는데,
We've collected the rest
of the grenade fragments.
전엔 본적 없는 물건입니다.
Looks like only one was used.
Get everything
모두 에비한테 갖다줘, 지금.
네...
to Abby now.
All right.
빨리!
Now!
지난 48시간 동안 이 배로 운송된
I want a list of every delivery
모든 수화물 명단을 가져와.
비숍?
this ship's received
in the past 48 hours. Bishop?
피해자 신원을 확인했습니다.
We've I.D.'d
the victim--
케더린 고메즈 상병.
Petty Officer Third Class
Katherine Gomez.
이 배로 배치된지
Assigned to the ship
3주밖에 안됐어요. 에, 또..
목격자 면담은?
only three weeks ago and...
Witness interviews?
그게, 이제 시작하려구요..
Well, we were just
about to get started.
함내 병실을 비울 예정이고,
TONY: Sick bay just
gave us clearance.
병원 소식을 기다리고 있었어요.
We're just waiting to hear
from the hospital.
함내 병실.. 거기서 하면 좋겠군. 가지.
Sick bay-- that's where
we start. Let's go.
자, 빨리, 가자구..
Come on,
let's move.
저희가 할 수 있습니다.
We can handle it.
뭐?
What?
Bishop and I
비숍과 제가 목격자 면담 할 수 있어요, 그게 더 났구요.
can handle the interviews--
might be better.
났나구?
Better?
뭐가 났다는 거냐, 디노조?
What's better, DiNozzo?
무슨 소릴 하고 싶은거야? 해봐.
What are you trying
to say? Spit it out.
그게요, 제 생각엔 너무..
Well, your...
bedside manner might be...
감정을 앞세우고 계세요..
(exhales) You might be
too close to this.
좀 냉정해지잔 얘기네, 제스로!
DUCKY: He's saying
take a breath, Jethro!
우리 모두 말일세
It's good advice for all of us.
(phone ringing)
에밀리, 엄마 전화는 그만 사용하라고 했지?
Emily, why are you still using
your mother's phone?
특별한 사람한테 걸때만 사용해요.
Only to call certain people.
지금 만나고 싶어요..
I need to see you right away.
사이다나 물 좀 갖다줄까??
Get you a soda or some
water or something, Em?
아뇨, 전 거품없는 라떼만 마셔요, 글고, 별로 오래 안걸려요..
No. I just had a low-foam latte,
and this won't take long.
한시간 만에, 토론대회 준결승까지 갔는걸요..
I've got debate
quarterfinals in an hour.
고등학생 토론경연?
신입생이자, 학교 대표팀 주장이랍니다.
High school debate?
I am varsity captain as a freshman.
토론이 적성에 맞나봐요.
Arguing's pretty much
in my blood.
전화로 얘기해도 됐을텐데 말이다..
We could have done
this over the phone.
아뇨, 전화론 안돼요.
No, we couldn't.
아침에, 우리 아빠 빼내주신거 알아요.
I know about you bailing out
my dad this morning.
정확하게 말하면, 빼내준건 아니다.
Wasn't exactly
bailing him out.
아빠가 요새 좀 힘든 상황이야.
전 어린애가 아녜요,
He's going through a tough time.
Don't soft-pedal me,
깁스 아저씨..
Uncle Gibbs.
아빤, 요새, 대머리 미치광이 같다구요
He looks nuts
with that bald head.
잠복근무 때문이야.
It's an undercover
operation.
그걸 믿으라는 거예요?
You don't believe that.
지난 주엔, 면도를 하루에 두번씩이나 했다구요
Last week he shaved it
twice in one day.
아빨 도와줘야 할 때란 거죠.
Said it helps him
feel clean.
엄마가 죽은 후,
(sighs)
Since Mom died,
아빤...
he's been...
화내고,
angry...
슬퍼하고, 자기파괴적이고..
bitter, self-destructive...
오, 그리고 술까지..
술을 너무 마셔대요.
oh, and... drunk--
he's drinking way too much.
아저씬, 어떤 상황인지 아시잖아요
You know what
he's experiencing.
도와주려해도, 제말은 듣지 않아요
I try to help,
but he doesn't listen to me,
그리고, 계속 하기엔 저도 슬프다구요...
and I've got my own grief
to work through.
넌 좀 어떠니?
괜찮은 날도 있고.. 끔찍한 날도 있죠.
How's that going?
Some good days... some awful.
근데, 다른 십대들처럼 생활하지 못한다면,
All compounded by being
a teenager who can't
전 더 악화될거예요..
be expected to maintain
a teenage social calendar
괜한 걱정이면 좋겠지만,
if I'm too busy
worrying about...
아빠가 잘못되거나 아니면, 누군가 다칠거 같단 말예요.
my father hurting himself
or anyone else.
그래, 내가 얘기해보마.
아뇨..
Okay, I'll talk to him.
No.
좀 도와주세요..
Help him.
꼭요..
Please.
알았다..
I will.
고마워요..
Thank you.
????
오래됐지만, 아주 나쁜거야, 맥기
ABBY: It's an oldie
but a baddy, McGee.
러시아제 RKG-3 대전차 수류탄.
McGEE:
Russian RKG-3 antitank grenade.
람보 영화에 나왔잖아
Straight out
of a Rambo movie.
사실, 그 전에 개발된거지.
Actually, it dates back
further than that.
이라크, 아프가니스탄 같은데선 아직도 사용된다구..
They still keep showing up
in Iraq and Afghanistan.
그래..
Yeah, and...
이거..
here.
추적할만한거 없을까?
Any shot at tracing it?
이봐, 맥기
Come on, McGee.
이 파편에서 뭔가 나온다면,
You know, if
there is anything
(phone ringing)
on these grenade fragments
틀림없이 세르게이한테 이어질테고,
that'll lead us
back to Sergei,
내가 꼭 발견할꺼야..
I will find it.
네, 토니?
Yeah, Tony?
벌써요?
Already?
네, 금방 올라갈께요.
Okay, I'll be right up.
둘이 방금 현장에서 돌아왔는데, 깁스가 벌써 보고하란데..
(exhales) Gibbs wants an update,
and they just
got back from the ship.
니가 그랬잖아, 깁스 열받았다고..
You said yourself
Gibbs is on fire.
저렇게 화내는건, 절대 본적없을 거야, 애비
Like you've never
seen before, Abby.
전에도 봤어..
We've seen it.
이번만큼은 아냐.
분명히 말하는데,
Not like this.
I'm telling you,
이번에도 세르게이를 놓친다면,
if Sergei gets away again,
우린, 지옥의 끝에서 깁스를 만나게 될거야
there's not a level of hell
below where Gibbs is right now.
그럼, 이번엔 놓칠 수도 없겠군
Then we can't let him
get away again.
고메즈 상병은 요리담당이구요,
Petty Officer Gomez
was a culinary specialist
폭탄이 터졌을 때 주방에 대기중이였습니다
setting up a catering station
when the bomb went off.
함내 병실에 있는 목격자 중,
As for the witness interviews,
no one in the ship's sick bay
폭발 진원지를 알고있는 사람은 없었구요.
could say where
the blast originated.
세르게이 사진은 보여줬나?
Did you show them
Sergei's mug shot?
그들 포함해서 모두에게 보여줬는데, 본 사람이 없습니다.
Them and everyone else--
no one reported seeing him.
그러면, 세르게이가 직접 그 망할 폭탄을 장치한건 아니겠군..
FORNELL: Well, hell, it's
not like Sergei would deliver
the bomb personally.
투바이어스..
껴들어서 미안하군..
Tobias...
Sorry to interrupt.
하던 얘기 계속 하게
Just got word
about the ship.
그럼 자넨 떠나는 중일테고 말야..
And you're on leave.
Not any longer.
안돼지.. FBI에서 도와주러 온거니까.
(clears throat)
FBI is here to help.
계속하지..
Continue.
음..
Uh...
계속해
Go.
노포크 병원으로 후송된 두명의 피해자가 더 있습니다.
There were
two other victims
that were taken
to Norfolk Memorial.
둘다 수술중인데, 회복하는 데로 즉시 인터뷰 하겠습니다.
Both are still in surgery,
but we'll
interview them
as soon as they're able.
애비는 수류탄 파편의 지문 확인 중이구요.
Abby's checking the
grenade fragments for prints.
수류탄 파편?
Grenade fragments?
이리와, 커피나 마시자..
아냐, 괜찮아..
Let's get a cup of coffee.
No, I'm good.
수류탄을 쓴건가?
이봐, 이리와. 빨리.
He used a grenade?
Hey, I'm not asking. Come on.
이봐, 왜 이러는거야?
Hey. What are you doing?
자네야 말로 지금 왜 이러는 거야?
What are you doing?
깁스, 포넬, 둘다 올라오세요
VANCE:
Gibbs and Fornell, my office.
당장.
Now.
단지 수면 부족일 뿐입니다, 레온.
FORNELL: It's just
a lack of sleep, Leon.
누구보다 잘할거라는 거 알잖아요.
You know it better
than anybody.
깁스도 마찬가지고..
Same with Gibbs.
세르게이를 잡기 전까진, 제게 안식은 없어요
Until Sergei is dead,
there's no peace.
아뇨, 깁스완 달리, 당신은 먼저
But unlike Gibbs,
you've let your demons
자신의 문제를 해결해야 해요
get the better of you.
아직도 술냄새가 납니다.
I can smell it on you.
블러드 메리 딱 한잔 했을 뿐예요. 반주로.
One Bloody Mary!
With lunch!
폭파사건 알기 전에 말입니다.
Before I heard
about the bombing.
깁스와 커피 마시러 갈 참이였고..
Gibbs and I were
just getting coffee.
잠시 밖에 나가계시죠.
세르게이는 제 겁니다.
I need you to wait outside.
Look, I deserve a shot at Sergei.
다른 누구도 안돼요.
다시 말하죠,
More than anyone.
And I need
깁스와 나눌 얘기가 있으니, 밖에 나가 기다리세요.
to have a word with Gibbs,
so please have a seat outside.
세르게이를 잡고 싶긴 한건가?
(quietly): You want
a shot at him or not?
그를 감싸줄 순 없어요, 깁스
시간이 조금 필요한 거야.
We can't cover for him, Gibbs.
Give him some time.
내가 얘기해 보겠네.
무슨 얘기요?
Let me talk to him.
And say what?
다른 사람 얘길 들을 수 있는 상태로 보입니까?
Does he look like he's listening
to anybody right now?
그의 모든 경력이 달린 문제야, 레온, 인생말야.
This is his whole career on
the line, Leon, his life.
당신 인생은 아닌가요, 깁스?
And what about
your life, Gibbs?
지금 상태론, 자신은 물론 동료요원과 우리까지 위험하게 만들겁니다.
He's a danger to himself,
his fellow agents and to us.
FBI가 아직 모른다면, 알려야 합니다.
FBI has to know,
if they don't already.
깁스, 나도 이러긴 싫은데,
Gibbs, this kills me,
그를 감싸줄 순 없어요, 당신도 알잖아요..
but we can't cover for him,
and you know it.
윌트 부국장님 부탁합니다.
Assistant Director
Wilt, please.
(dial tone droning)
(sets handset
in cradle)
이게 지금 뭐하는 짓입니까?
Have you lost your damn mind?
I will take
내가 다 책임지겠네
full responsibility.
포넬을 수렁에서 빼내겠네
I will get Fornell
out of the way.
세르게이를 잡기위해 팀을 떠나있도록 하지.
뭐라구요?
I'll leave my team to go after Sergei.
You're gonna do what?
팀을 떠난다구요?
보기보다 능력있는 친구들이네, 레온
You're gonna leave your team?
They're more than capable, Leon,
전화로 지휘하면 돼
and I'll be a phone call away.
깁스, 지금 세르게이 미쉬노프 얘길 하고 있는 겁니다
Gibbs, this is Sergei Mishnev
we're talking about.
어쩌면 내 얘길지도 몰라, 너무 개입했거든..
And maybe it's me
that's too close.
아니, 나와 포넬 둘의 문제야..
Maybe it's me and Fornell.
And you think
누가 보내주긴 한답니까?
그게 싫으면 날빼..
I'll just let you?
That or bench me.
아님 믿던가..
Or trust me.
정말, 이런날이 올지는 몰랐네요.
Well, I never thought
I'd see the day.
도대체 어딜 가겠다는 겁니까, 깁스?
And where are you
gonna go, Gibbs?
어떻게 그를 잡겠다는 거냐구요?
Where are you gonna take him?
(grumbles)
(revs engine)
여기가 어디야?
(engine turns off)
Where are we?
이리와. 짐내리는 것 좀 도와줘.
Come on. Help me unload.
아 정말 이게 뭐야..
장난치냐?
Holy Jeremiah Johnson.
Are you kidding me?!
(exhales sharply)
자네가 말한건 이게 아니잖아.
(shivers)
This is not what we agreed to.
세르게이를 쫏아가자고 했잖나..
아니.
You said we were going after Sergei.
No, no.
자네가 그랬지. 난 같이 가자고 했을 뿐야..
You said that.
I said let's go.
그게 그 말이잖아!
Which would imply agreement!
도대체 여기서 뭐하자구?
What the hell are
we doing out here?
잠깐..
Wait a minute.
간섭? 이게 그거야?
An intervention?
Is that what this is?
간섭이 필요하다고 생각하나?
미쳤나! 모, 최근 좀 않좋았던건 인정해, 그래,
Do you think you need one?
No! I mean, last night was bad, yes,
근데, 세상을 바꿔야 될만큼 나빴던 것도 아냐.
but-but not bad enough
to make any kind of New-Age
절대 아니라고!
come-to-Jesus
even remotely necessary!
오, 잘됐네, 그럼 이건 간섭이 아냐.
Oh, good,
that's not what this is.
천천히 죽어가진 말자구, 투바이어스.
No more slow-motion
suicide, Tobias.
죽고싶다면 말야,
You want to kill yourself...
나도 좋아..
fine with me.
마셔.
Go ahead.
나랑 같이 가자구..
I'll even come with you.
????
(trembling breath)
깁스한텐 아직도 연락없어요?
Still no word from Gibbs?
지난밤 떠난 이후론 쥐뿔도 없어
Not a peep since
he left last night.
후..
Huh.
포넬을 돕기위해서라곤 해도,
I can't believe he'd leave
at a time like this,
이렇게 훌쩍 떠나다니, 믿기질 않네요
even to help Fornell.
Well,
모, 가족이 우선인거죠. 토니의 용감한 제안이 없었어도,
family first-- not to mention
your brave suggestion
사적으로 사건과 가까워진건 사실이니까..
that he might just be too close.
지금 비웃는거지?
Are you mocking me?
그게요.. 분명 마음에 담아두셨을 거예요
Well... he obviously
took it to heart.
좋아.
Okay.
첫째, 날 아주 끔찍하게 생각해주는군..
Number one, that's adorable.
둘째, 깁스는 절대 사건을 피하지 않아
And number two, Gibbs would
never bail on a case,
세르게이 사건일지라도..
much less a Sergei case;
내가 제안했다 해도.. 해도, 해도, 해도..
and much, much less
at my suggestion.
뭔가 계획이 있다면 얘긴 다르죠..
Unless he had a plan.
(phone ringing)
특수요원 맥기입니다.
Special Agent McGee.
오, 잘됐네요, 정말..
Oh, great, great.
알려주셔서 감사합니다. 바로 가겠습니다.
Thanks for letting us know.
We'll be right there.
병원요. 피해자 둘 다 깨어났고,
Hospital.
Both victims are awake
면담할 정도로 상태가 좋아졌답니다.
and well enough
to be interviewed.
아, 깁스의 계획 말인데요, 맥기..
Hey. Gibbs's plan, McGee--
계획이 뭘까요?
오, 그건 나도 모르지..
what do you think it is?
Oh, I have no idea.
단지, 뭔가 있기전까진, 절대 떠날 분이 아냐.
I just know that he wouldn't
leave unless he had one.
잘 아는군, 맥탐정. (Maggie+detective)
I'm with you, McTuitive.
뭔가 꿍꿍이가 있는거야..
Gibbs has to be to something.
(cell phone ringing)
오...
Oh.
우리가 방금 맞췄나봐..
Maybe we're about
to find out.
좋은 아침입니다, 보스.
Morning, boss.
그래, 우린 어디에 있지, 디노조? (사건은 어떻게 됐지?)
Okay. Where are we, DiNozzo?
저흰 여기 큰 오렌지 색 사무실에 있구요,
We are in the big orange room.
우린 어딨는지 아는데, 보스는 어디세요?
We know where are.
Where are you?
맥기는 아직 내 전화도 추적 안하고 모하는거야?
McGee hasn't
pinged my phone yet?
사실은요, 보스, 그게, 했습니다.
Actually, boss, yeah, I-I did.
정말요?
왜 말을 안해?
Really?
You didn't tell us?
그게, 추적을 원하시는 지 몰랐거든요.
Well, I didn't know
if he'd want me to.
추적하지마.
I don't.
아무도 여기오게 하지마.
And I don't want
someone coming here
니 목이 떨어지는 한이 있어도..
when you do tell them
after you hang up.
알겠습니다, 그럼 저흰 뭘해도 될까요?
All right, so what
can we do for you?
진행상황은 보고하는게 좋을거다
Well, for starters,
you can give me an update.
지난 48시간 동안 전함에서 받은 수화물 명단을 뒤졌습니다.
Well, we're still combing
the ship's deliveries
the last 48 hours.
아직 수상한 건 없습니다.
Nothing yet.
지금 막 병원으로 가려구요.
We were just about to
leave for the hospital.
맥기가 병원에서 전화 받았...
McGee got a call because the...
(retching)
(retching continues loudly
over phone)
보스, 누굴 목조르는 중이세요?
Boss, is that
you choking,
아님 누가 목조르고 있어요?
or are you choking someone?
빨리 가봐.
Got to go.
목격자 면담결과 보고하고..
Call me after the interviews.
저기, 잠깐만요, 저기요~~
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
뭐 다른 말씀하실건 없으세요?
Is there anything
you want to tell us?
그런거 있잖아요, 계획 같은건 없으세요?
Yeah, like, is there a...
plan of any kind?
계획?
You need a plan?
세르게이를 잡는거다
Catch Sergei.
쬐금 애매하군..
That's a little vague.
잠깐..
Wait.
누구였나?
Who was that?
잘잤니, 아가.
Morning, sunshine.
자네 팀 아니였어?
Was that your team?
진행상황은 어떻데?
Is there any progress?
(shudders)
열심히 하고 있대.
They're working on it.
잘잤나?
Did you sleep well?
정말 싫다, 깁스.
I hate you, Gibbs.
지금 우리가 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
내 핸드폰은 어딨어?
What are we doing out here?
Where's my cell phone?
그걸 내가 어찌알아?
자네거 줘봐. 에밀리하고 통화해야 해.
How would I know that?
Give me yours. I need to call Emily.
아냐, 괜찮아, 에밀리는..
No, no, no. Hey, hey,
Emily's fine.
친구와 같이 있어.
내가 통화했네.
She's staying with friends.
I talked to her.
자네가?
You called?
그애도 알고 있나?
아니.
She's in on this?
No.
에밀리는 괜찮아.
She's okay.
좋아, 내가 졌어.
Fine. You win.
다음은 뭔가?
What now?
다음이라니?
이제 뭘 할거냐구?
"What now" what?
What do we do next?
북이나 치자구? 이 오두막에서?
Bang drums? Sweat lodge?
재주도 넘고?
Squirrel juggling?
오, 그렇단 말이지?
Oh, really?
지금 내손에 도끼를 쥐어주는게 자네 생각이란거지?
You think it's a good idea
to hand me an ax right now?
그래, 추워 죽겟네, 투바이어스.
Well, yeah.
It's cold, Tobias.
더 추워질거네.
It's getting colder.
그건, 음..
That, uh...
말 안듣고 날뛴 벌야,
that ass wound of yours...
엉덩이 때리기지, 알겠나?
bet it's acting up, huh?
커피 만들겠네.
I'll make coffee.
우유, 쬐금만 넣어줘.
Milk, two-percent.
블랙야.
Black.
그렇겠지. 설탕 비스무리한것도 없지?
Right.
You have any fake sugar?
왜 이런걸 묻고 앉아있는걸까?
Why do I even ask?
그러니까, 당신은 군소속이 아니란거죠?
So you're not military?
아, 아닙니다.
MAN:
Uh, no, sir.
사실, 전함에선 처음 일해봤어요
In fact, that was my first time
on a Navy ship.
나갈땐 그렇게 신나하더니,
He was so excited
when he left the shop.
이 꼴이 됐네요.
Now look at him.
근데, 가게라면?
Sorry. The shop?
아, 영상과 음향을 다뤄요
Uh, video and sound.
해군에서,
Navy had us
오찬에 참석 못한 분들을 위해
running a satellite for anyone
위성중계를 맡아달라 했어요
who couldn't attend
the breakfast.
해군성 장관님 처럼요.
아, 장관님..
Like your Navy Secretary.
Our SECNAV, yeah.
전함에 계셨나요, 바로스씨?
아뇨.
Were you there, Mr. Boulos?
No.
전 이제 장부나 적습니다.
I just do the books now.
장비는 프랭키가 담당하는데,
Frankie's in charge
of the new equipment.
아깝지만, 다 날아갔네요.
Which we don't care
about losing, by the way.
아들녀석이 참 소중하게 다룬건데..
All that matters
is my boy is alive.
프랭키, 폭발 전에
Frankie,
is there anything specific
뭔가 이상한 점은 없었나요?
that you can recall
before the explosion?
동료들은 다 괜찮았어요
The crew was nice.
음향 체크 중이였는데,
I was running a sound check,
어뢰에 맞았구나..했어요
and the last thing I remember
그거 밖에 기억나지 않네요.
was thinking maybe
we'd been torpedoed.
(groans)
케이티가 죽었다는게 믿기질 않습니다.
I just can't believe
Katie's dead.
상병하곤 친했나요?
You and the petty officer
were friends?
아뇨, 처음봤는데, 친해졌죠.
She was new, but yeah.
제가 본 가장 행복한 군인이였습니다.
Happiest CS-Three
anyone ever met.
폭발 당시 가까이 계셨나요?
And you were nearby
when the explosion happened?
오찬 준비를 하면서,
We were setting out pastries
우리가 다 먹어버리자고 떠들고 있었는데,
and joking about
eating them all.
갑자기..그녀가..
And the next thing I knew, sh...
케이티가 방을 가로질러 날아갔어요
she went flying across the room.
그녀의 부모님들..
Her parents.
항상 부모님들 얘길 했는데..
She talked about them
all the time.
알고 계신가요?
Do they know yet?
네.
해군 항공편으로 오고 계세요
Yeah.
Navy's flying them in now.
도대체 누가 이런짓을 벌인걸까요?
Who would do something
like this?
실례합니다, 토니?
Excuse me. Tony?
감사합니다.
All right. Thank you.
난 세르게이를 증오해. 말했던가?
I hate Sergei.
Did I say that?
네, 저두요(미 투 ㅠㅠ)
Yeah, me, too.
저두요(미 쓰리 ㅠㅠ)
Me three.
근데, 괜찮다면,
But if you don't mind,
I just need to vent
잠깐 화풀이 좀 하러 갔다올께요
about something else
for a second.
오, 그래. 우리 어따 화풀이 할까?
Oh, no. What did we do?
아뇨, 저만요.
No, not you.
제이크, 그이가 막 전화했네요
Jake. He just called.
지난주 깁스하고 그이하고 했던
You know that dinner
저녁식사는 어떻게 된거예요?
he and Gibbs ended up
having last week?
너하고 토니는 차버렸잖아.
The one that you
and Tony ditched.
차긴 누가 차. 우린 일하고 있었어.
We did not ditch.
We were working.
근데, 그것때메 둘이 죽고 못사는 친구가 됐어.
But it did leave
them to be BFFs.
우리가 깨닫기도 전에 말이죠.
More than any of us realized.
들어보니까, 깁스가 제이크한테 정보를 캐냈데요
Apparently, Gibbs
asked Jake to share Intel.
러시아인과 팔레스타인인의 관계에 대해 NAS가 갖고 있는 모든 정보요
Everything NSA has on
Russian-Palestinian relations.
세르게이 미쉬노프, 안톤 파블렌코 같은 사람들...
Sergei Mishnev,
Anton Pavlenko...
보스는 아무말씀 없으시던데..
He didn't say anything
to us about it.
아무한테도 말하면 안된다고 하셨데요.
Because he didn't want us
or anyone knowing.
근데, 어떻게 제이크는 나한테도 말을 안할 수 있죠?
But how could Jake not tell me?
결혼이란게 그런거지, 근데 말하는 걸 보니 이미 불었나본데..
Well, that's a marriage thing,
but it sounds like he just did.
오늘 아침 깁스 전화받고나서,
Only because Gibbs called
early this morning
제이크한테 관련정보 다 내놓으라고 했어요
and told Jake to send us
everything he had
그거 보면 우리가 뭘해야 할지 알 수 있을거예요
and that we would know
what to do with it.
오.. 그게 계획의 일부였겠군?
Oh. Could that be part of a plan?
(cell phone chiming)
방금 이메일이 왔네요
Well, the e-mail
just came through.
엄청 큰 파일예요
It's a huge file.
가요.
Let's go.
내가 버렸어.
I dumped it.
뭘?
What?
버번말야, 이제 없다구.
The bourbon-- it's gone.
자네가 내 엄마라도 되나?
What are you, my mother?
대체 뭘 하려는 거야?
What are you trying to prove?
내가 뭘 먹는지까지 감시할 필욘 없잖아
I don't need you
monitoring my intake.
아, 감시할 필요가 있어 보여.
Ah, it seems to me you do.
감시할 필요없어.
Well, I don't.
여기도 필요없구.
And I don't need this.
아, 사실, 나도 그래..
Yeah, well, neither do I...
근데 어떡해.. 여기 왔는데.
but here we are.
(cup clatters on floor)
그만두자구..
I'm done.
그만둬? 뭘?
"Done." With what?
자학하는거?
Embarrassing yourself?
아님, FBI 요원이란걸 창피해하는거?
Or-or maybe you mean
embarrassing the badge.
하긴, 둘다 꽤나 잘하긴 했지..
You've done a good job at both.
Oh...
겨우 이정돈가, 아가씨?
That all you got, Alice?
Yah!
(grunts)
(coughs)
정신 좀 차렸어?
Do you feel better?
세르게이 잡으러 가야돼
We should be in D.C.
looking for Sergei.
이런 상태론 안돼
Not in this
condition.
세르게이 따윈 잊어버려
Geez, forget
about Sergei.
정말 신경쓰이는게 뭔데?
What's really
bothering you?
의사 흉내지마, 깁스. 자넨 자격없어
Don't Freud me, Gibbs.
You're not qualified.
뭔 소린지 알잖아.
You know what
I'm asking.
됐어.
내 탓이라고 생각하잖아
Back off.
You blame me.
제스로..
Jethro...
괜찮아, 투바이어스
It's okay, Tobias.
내 탓 맞아
I blame me.
내가 죽게 만든거야..
I'm the one who got her killed.
(sighs)
그때 그 지붕에 없었으면,
If Diane wasn't
on that rooftop,
다이앤은 죽지 않았을 거야
she would be alive.
그리고, 나때문이란걸 알면서도
And you wouldn't
be walking around
모르는 척 하려고 자네가 괴롭지도 않았을테고..
pretending like I wasn't
the one who put her there.
그래, 다 자네때문야..
그래.
So it's all about you.
Yeah.
다 나 때문야..
It is all about me.
자네가 이렇게 된거도,
And it's about you,
다이앤이 죽은거도, 술에 취한것도,
and it's about Diane,
and it's about
모두 다 나 때문이라고..
the drinking, and
it's about all of it.
자네 탓이 아냐, 친구..
No, my friend.
내탓이지..
It's just me.
내가 그녈 죽인거라고..
I killed her.
다 내탓인데 누굴 원망하겠나..
No one to blame but myself.
이젠 진짜 한잔하고 싶군..
And now I really need a drink.
(sighs)
NAS 정보에서 나온게 좀 있나?
That NSA Intel give us anything?
아, 그게 방금 시작했습니다. 국장님.
Oh, we are just
getting started, Director,
근데, 찾아 볼게 많네요.
and there is a whole lot
to comb through.
아프가니스탄의 러시아 관련 정보,
Stuff in here about
the Soviets in Afghanistan,
이슬람 테러리스트 등등..
the mujahideen...
잠깐만요. 세르게이와
Wait a second.
Got something about Sergei
파블렌코와 관해 뭔가 찾았어요
and the Russian Counselor
Pavlenko.
우리 "친구" 안톤 말이군..
Our "friend" Anton.
뭔가?
둘이 알고지낸 지 꽤 됐네요.
What is it?
They go way back.
대학시절부턴데요..
All the way to college.
성페테스부르크 대학시절에
They competed at
Saint Petersburg University
바이애슬론으로 좋은 경쟁자였네요.
in the biathlon.
스키타면서 총쏘는
Isn't that the one where they
cross-country ski
그거 말하는건가요?
그렇지.
and shoot rifles?
TONY: Yeah.
무한도전에서 말야,
As random Olympic sports go,
트램펄린 위에서 투우 하잖아..그거하고 비슷한 거야..
it's sort of the equivalent of
bullfighting on a trampoline.
그럴듯 하군..
계속하게.
That explains a lot.
Go on.
당시 둘은 올림픽 팀 선발을 놓고
Well, they were friendly rivals
for a while,
경쟁할 정도로 좋은 맞수였는데,
contending for
the Soviet Olympic team.
둘다 탈락하고 나선,
When neither of them
made the cut,
파블렌코는 법대에 갔고,
Pavlenko went
to law school
세르게이는 아프가니스탄의 헤로인 판매에 손을 댔네요.
and Sergei discovered
the Afghan heroin trade.
더 해보게..
Explains even more.
대학시절 절친이 범죄자가 된게
Like his soft spot
그의 약점이 된거죠
for an old college buddy
gone bad.
파블렌코는 차갑게 변했고, 우린 헤어졌네
Making Pavlenko less of
a cold, duplicitous creep,
애증은 깊어갔고, 더 멀어졌네.
and more of a sentimental,
duplicitous creep.
(dog barks in distance)
(grunts)
세르게이.
Sergei...
(speaking Russian)
여긴 미국야. 영어로 해.
This is America. Speak English.
우리 둘뿐야, 장담하지
We are quite alone,
I assure you.
그래? 지난번 니가 장담했을땐,
Yeah? The last time
you assured me,
콜라 반도에서 내 좋은 부하들을 잃었지
I lost good men in
the Kola Peninsula.
그건 장담이 아니였어
It was no assurance.
경고였지.
It was a warning.
NCIS는 건들지 말라고 했잖은가.
To stay away
from NCIS.
니가 무시하는 바람에, 지금 어떻게 됐지?
You chose to ignore it,
and where are you now?
수류탄이나 터트리고, 잠수타고 있잖아?
Setting off hand grenades
and hiding in alleys?
넘어지는걸 두려워 하지마, 안톤.
다시 일어나면 되니까.
It's not how you fall, Anton.
It's how you rise.
이 말 기억나나?
Remember that one?
그래서 내가 연락한거다.
Which is why I called you.
니가 일어나는걸 도우려고, 세르게이.
To help you rise, Sergei.
러시아 정부의 제안이야
With a proposal from
the Russian government.
러시아는 날 죽이려고 해
The government
that wants me dead.
니 망명을 위해 내가 설득했어
I convinced them
to give you asylum.
한가지 조건만 들어주면, 아무죄도 묻지않을꺼야.
Complete immunity,
on one condition.
괜찮아 보이는군
This should be good.
깁스를 죽여라
Kill Gibbs.
니 가족의 복수를 너무 오래 미뤄왔어.
Your vendetta
has dragged on long enough.
이것으로 종지부를 찍자.
We need it to end.
이제야 허락해주는 건가?
And I have your blessing now?
왜 지금이지?
Why now?
왜 갑자기 마음이 바뀐거지?
Why the sudden change of heart?
깁스한테 목숨도 빚졌잖아
You owe Gibbs your life.
그렇게 생각하는 거 안다, 한번 그랬었지, 근데..
I know you believe that,
like I once did, but...
근데 뭐?
That what? What?
말해봐. 날 설득해보라구.
Tell me. Convince me.
넬리 베닌.
그 과학자.
Nelly Benin.
The scientist.
살아있어.
She's alive.
깁스가 그녈 죽여 날 구한건 계략이였어
Gibbs killing her
to save my life was a ruse.
교묘한 책략으로 그녀의 망명을 도운거지
An elaborate sleight of hand
to help her defect.
잘알겟지만, 우린 망명자를 용서하지 않아
And you know we
don't like defectors.
그리고 난, 누가 날 갖고 노는걸 싫어해
And I don't like
being played for a fool.
언제 실행하게?
Is there a timetable?
당장.
Now.
오늘말야.
Today.
그가 어딨는지 알고 있어
My people know
exactly where he is.
몇시간 내에 그놈 앞에 데려다주지
I can have you there
in a matter of hours.
(bird singing, duck quacking)
이건 미친짓야
FORNELL:
This is insane.
분명히 식료품 가방에서 참치캔을 봤다구
I'm sure I saw cans of tuna
in those grocery bags.
어렸을 때 낚시해본적 없나?
You never fished as a kid?
그건 여름이야,
In the summer,
한여름.
sure.
핑거 레이크 호수.
Finger Lakes.
참 좋았지
I loved it.
그 때로 돌아갔으면 좋겠어
I should get back to it.
지금은 할 수 없는 것들이 참 많았지
But there's a lot I don't
do enough of anymore.
밖에 나가서, 내 손으로 말야..
Get outdoors,
work with my hands...
(reel spinning)
와, 이거 좀 봐
Whoa, look at this.
그래.
Yeah.
감아. 침착하게.
Reel her in. Steady.
그래, 알았어.
Yeah, I got it.
(grunts)
멋진걸!
Beauty!
이거봐.
(laughs)
Look at that.
둘이 먹고도 남겠는데..
It's big enough for two.
누가 나눠준데?
I'm not sharing.
자네도 한마리 잡아보라구
Let's get you one.
이게 지금 확실한건가?
Am I reading this right?
세르게이가 이스라엘 출신이라고?
Sergei is originally
from Israel?
1965년 생입니다.
Born in 1965.
아버지, 디미트리는
Father, Dimitri,
러시아 장교로 거기 근무했구요.
was a Russian officer
stationed there.
어머니에 대한건 없네요
Nothing here about his mother.
잠깐, 여기 뭔가 있어
Wait a second,
I got something on her.
이 보고서에 의하면, 어머니는
This report says his
mother was a doctor,
팔래스타인계 사우디 국적의 의사였답니다
a Saudi national with
Palestinian roots.
10살때 아버지가 러시아로 데려가는 바람에
Apparently, the
father took Sergei
back to Russia
when he was ten,
어머니완 떨어져 산 것처럼 보이네요
leaving his
mother behind.
바로 거기서부터 시작됐군요
Birth of some issues
right there.
왜요?
What?
제가 뭐 까먹은거라도?
Am I missing something?
혹시 그것때문이라고 생각해요?
You think that's
what's driving him?
그것때문에 화난게 확실해.
No wonder the
guy's pissed off.
Uh... Whoa, whoa, whoa.
말해줘요. 빨리.
Details. Now.
저 책상 쓰던 자네 전임자말일세,
Your predecessor
at that desk,
지바 다비드라고, 이복 오빠가 있었네.
Ziva David,
had a half-brother.
아리 하스와리. 아빠가 같죠. 저도 알아요.
Ari Haswari. Same father.
I know the story.
아리의 어머니도 팔레스타인 계 의사였어
Ari's mother was also a doctor
with Palestinian roots.
그러니까, 어쩌면 세르게이와 아리가 말야.
So it's quite possible
that Sergei and Ari were...
이복형제일 수도 있다는 거지.
Half-brothers.
세르게이의 복수에 대해
Which would explain the depth
깁스한테 설명해주는게 좋겟네
of his hatred for Gibbs.
연락할까요?
근데말야.. 깁스가
Should we call him?
McGEE: Well, I don't know
이 얘길 오두막에서 듣게되면,
what he'd do with that
information at the cabin,
맨 주먹으로 곰사냥하는 거 보다 더 한짓이라도 할거야.
other than punch out
a grizzly bear.
TONY: It does open up a
whole new world
반 세르게이 동맹의 새로운 시대가 열리는 거지..
of possible allies
for Sergei.
(phone beeps)
맥깁니다.
McGee.
그래, 누가 올꺼야?
ABBY:
Okay, which one of you wants
깁스, 깁스, 깁스, 깁스 대신에..
to be Gibbs Gibbs
Gibbs Gibbs Gibbs?
지금 갈께, 애비
Be right there, Abbs.
그렇게 나쁜 테이블은 아니였는데 말야,
I mean, it wasn't
a bad little table.
다이앤은 항상 테이블 다리하나에 종이성냥을 껴놓고
I mean, Diane would always
stick a matchbook under one leg
내가 다리길이를 잘못재서 이렇게 된거라고 탓하듯이,
to remind me that
I'd measured wrong,
절대 그걸 빼지 않더라구..
but she never
got rid of it.
아마 날 고문하려고 그랬을 거야..
Probably just to torture me,
I guess.
자네가 만든 걸 좋아했어
She liked that you built it.
모, 그런 걸 잘만들어내는 남자가 이상형이였을거야
Well, she was always a pushover
for that manly man stuff.
다 자네 때문야..
God knows it worked for you.
그건 모르겠는걸..
I don't know about that.
그녀가 재혼하려고 했던건, 내가 아니라 자네야
You're the one
she kept remarrying, not me.
그지?
Right?
지금 우리가 여기서 뭔짓거릴 하는거지?
What the hell are we doing here?
한마리면 충분하다 보네..
One fish is enough.
자네 팀에서 상황보고는 없어?
Where's your team
with those updates?
26조각의 수류탄 파편인데..
26 separate pieces
of grenade fragments,
어떤 조각에도 지문이 없어요
and there's not a single
fingerprint on any of them.
부분지문도 없더라구요.
Not even a partial.
그래서, 긴급안건이란게 뭔가, 슈토양?
So what's the urgency,
Miss Sciuto?
긴급안건은, 이런 종류의 수류탄은
The urgency is that
this type of grenade
혼자서는 절대 터질 수 없다는 거죠
doesn't go off
by itself.
그니까, 핀을 빼고, 던져야, 펑~ 한다는 거예요
I mean, you have
to turn the handle
and throw it,
and then boom.
기폭장치가 있어야 터지는 폭탄인데..
But the way this one exploded
required some type of detonator.
그걸 아직 찾지 못했거네.
Which we never found.
근데, 이걸보면 알거야
But you did find it.
아님 눈치라도 챌거라구..
Or at least
a piece of it.
이거 봐봐..
It's this, right here.
플라스틱 방울처럼 보이는데?
Looks like a blob of plastic.
그거야 플라스틱 방울이니까요..
That's because
it's a blob of plastic.
근데, 이게 녹기전에는요
But before it melted,
무지하게 부드러워서,
it was a highly sensitive,
소리의 특정 주파수에서조차 떨리는 종이처럼 얇은 플라스틱 시트였어요
paper-thin plastic sheet
that vibrates at certain
sound frequencies,
어떤 장치에 붙이든, 이게 방아쇠가 되는거죠.
triggering whatever device
it's attached to.
음향담당.
프랭키 부로스.
The A/V guy.
Frankie Boulos.
음향체크하던 중에, 수류탄이 폭발했다고 했어
He said that
the grenade exploded
while he was doing
a sound check.
그 남자 목소리로도 폭발시킬 수 있을까?
Could his voice have set it off?
모, 어떤 목소리냐에 따라 다르긴 한데..
It would depend
on his voice.
엄청 민감해서, 더 높은 주파수여야 해
I mean,
it's more sensitive
with higher-pitched
frequencies.
음향장치에 무지하게 가까워야 한다는 거지.
I mean, unless
the device was
super close to
the sound equipment.
아님, 음향장치 속에 설치돼 있었나?
Or if it was planted inside
the sound equipment?
좋아..
Oh, yeah.
이제야 좀 괜찮아 졌군.
Now, this is pretty great.
모가?
What?
아, 그렇군.
Oh, yeah.
(clears throat)
이봐, 좀 먹어봐.
Come on, man.
Gotta eat.
이따가...
Later, maybe.
그런걸 먹을만큼 배고프진 않아..
Not that hungry.
내가 또 물어볼 차례가 된건가?
Are you gonna make
me ask you again?
자네가 전에 말했잖아,
You mentioned before
다이앤과 내가 재혼하는거에 대해..
about Diane and me
getting remarried.
근데, 최종적으론, 그녀에 대해 확신이 없었나봐
In the end,
she wasn't really so sure.
원래 그런법야..
Natural to get
cold feet.
아니, 그거완 달라
No, it wasn't that.
언젠가, 밤에, 별것도 아닌걸로 다퉜거든
We were arguing one night
about something stupid.
뭐 때문인지 기억도 안나.
I don't even remember what.
근데, 내가 화가나서 말해버렸어
And in a fit of anger,
I told her
둘이 다시 합치고, 다시 시작하는게,
that our being together,
큰 실수 같다고 말야..
our rekindled romance,
was a big mistake.
그리고 뛰쳐나갔지..
And I stormed out.
다음날, 그녀한테서 전화가 왔어
Next day,
she called.
마침 기밀 회의중이라 못받았는데, 음성메세질 남겼더군
I was in a classified briefing,
so she left a voice mail.
그게 내가 핸드폰을 찾아야 되는 이유야
That's why I hope
I haven't lost my phone.
그녀의 목소릴 들을 수 있는 유일한 방법이거든..
It's the only way
I can still hear her voice.
이건 돌려주려고 했었어, 모, 어쨌든...
I was gonna give it back
to you, eventually, anyway.
안녕, 자기, 나야.
DIANE:
Hey, baby, it's me.
음, 근데, 어젯밤 일은 그냥 잊어버리면 안될까?
Um, look, can we just
forget last night?
그냥 제스로의 두번째 부인과 싸운걸로 하면..
Between Jethro's wife number two
in town and...
그냥, 되감아버리거나, 지워버리거나, 아무튼...
I don't know, let's hit rewind
or delete or whatever.
난 다시 합치는게 실수인것 같진 않아, 투바이어스
I don't think
we're a mistake at all, Tobias,
당신도 실수라고 생각하지 않았으면 해..
and I pray you don't, either.
이런 사소한 문제들은 잘 해결할 수 있다고 봐.
I know we can work through
the petty stuff.
제스로가 방금 만나자고 문자했어..
Jethro just texted me
to meet him,
이거 듣자마자 바로 전화해줘, 알았지?
but call me back
as soon as you can, okay?
사랑해, 투바이어스.
I love you, Tobias.
꼭 전화해.
Call me.
지금 한 말들..
Every word.
나도 그녀가 한말에 전부 동의해..
I agreed with
every word she said,
근데, 그녀한테 바로 전화하는 대신에..
but instead of
calling her right back,
사소한 일이라고 그냥 지나쳐버렸어
I chose to play it small.
별거아니라고..
Petty.
어디 한번 당해보라고...
Serves her right.
그랬는데, 그녀가 떠나더군..
And then she was gone.
죽음이 우릴 갈라 놨다고 생각하겠지만,
Died thinking
it might be over between us.
사실은 내가 그녈 얼마나 사랑했는지 몰랐던 거야..
Not truly knowing
how much I loved her.
아냐, 그녀는 알았을거야...
No, she knew.
큰 실수인거 같아..
"We're making a big mistake."
그게 그녀에게 해준
Those were the last words
내 마지막 말이였네..
she heard me say.
그것 때문에, 내 자신을 결코 용서할 수 없어.
And for that,
I can never forgive myself.
자네라면 용서가 되겠나?
Could you?
내 딸이 살아 있었다면 말야, 난 용서했을꺼야.
(choked up):
If I had a daughter, yeah.
에밀리는 그녀의 딸이야, 투바이어스.
That's her daughter, Tobias.
자네가 얼마나 사랑했었는지, 다이앤이 알았으면 좋겠어?
You want Diane to know
how much you love her?
에밀리가 자네한테 남겨진 유일한 기회야.
That's the only chance
you got left.
오..
Oh.
헤이..
Hey.
수사는 잘되고 있는거죠?
Is everything all right?
아침 면담 후 밝혀진게 있는데 말입니다,
Something's come up since
our interview this morning.
이 사진 좀 봐주세요.
We want to show you a photo.
그래요..
Okay.
어제 폭탄 터지기 전, 이 남자 본적 있나요?
Before the bomb
went off yesterday,
do you recall seeing this man?
잘 모르겠어요.
Uh, I don't know.
낯은 익는데..
He looks
kind of familiar.
낯은 익다?
Kind of?
Mm-hmm.
뭐하는 겁니까?
What is this?
이 아인 휴식이 필요해요
My son needs
his rest.
도대체 얼마나 더 이 애를 귀찮게 할거예요?
How many times are you
going to disturb him?
블로스 씨, 죄송합니다만..
McGEE:
Mr. Boulos, I'm sorry.
몇가지 물어볼게 더 있어서요
We... we have a few
more questions to ask.
뭐라고 얘기했어?
What did you tell them?
당신만큼 많은 얘길 한건 아니네요..
Not as much as you're
about to tell us.
끊지마.
GIBBS:
Hang on.
뭐라고?
What's that?
끝부분.. 끊기기 전에..
The last part.
You're breaking up.
잠깐, 다시 말해봐.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait, wait. Say it again.
들리나?
디노조!
Can you hear me?
DiNozzo!
디노조?
DiNozzo?
어떻게 된거야?
What's going on?
아.. 용의자를 잡았다는데,
Ah... they got a suspect,
근데.. 전화가 끊어져버렸어.
but... I lost him.
I got cut off.
용의자? 세르게이가 아니고?
A suspect? Not Sergei?
아니, 다른 사람인데, 관계가 있데..
No, somebody else,
but there's a connection.
심문하려고 데려왔다는 군. 자네 핸드폰 확인해봐.
They're bringing him in for
questioning. Check your cell.
다 똑같아.. 수신불가.
Same here-- no bars.
모, 어때? 가자구.
But who cares? Let's go!
가자구?
그래.
Go?
Yes.
세르게이와 관련있다면, 자네와 내가 심문해야지
If Sergei is involved, you and I
should do the questioning.
세르게이가 아냐, 다른 자라고.
But it's not Sergei;
it's somebody else,
그리고, 여기 일은 아직 안끝났고..
뭐?
and we're not done here yet.
What?
아냐, 다끝냈어..
Oh, yes, we are.
I'm done.
그렇게 생각해?
당연하지..
You think so?
I know so.
방금 여기 앉아있는데, 오랜만에, 처음으로
I was just sitting here,
feeling not lousy
괜찮다는 느낌이 들었네
for the first time
in I don't know when.
정말 고맙네, 깁스.
And I appreciate it, Gibbs.
내 간도 이제 괜찮아진것 같네..
Little wake-up call
to my liver.
예전엔 할 수 없었던 얘기도 다 후련하게 말했고.
Getting to say things out loud
that I never thought I'd say.
아직 무지개를 보며 노래부를 만큼은 아니지만,
어쨌든 준비가 됐네
I may not be whistling rainbows
just yet, but I got the message.
하룻밤이면 충분하네.
자네가 옳아.
One night is enough.
You're right.
딸 아이를 만나야겠어.
I need to see my little girl.
아직 아냐..
Not yet.
여기에서 내가 얻을 게 뭔가, 위로의 말?
What do I need here,
a safe word?
무슨 속셈야?
What's going on?
뭔가 다른게 있군.
There's something
else here.
나한테 숨기는게 뭐야?
What are you not telling me?
세르게이가 제 친구는 아닙니다.
Sergei is no friend.
어렸을 때 팔레스타인에서 함께 자랐고,
We played together
as boys in Palestine
젊었을 때, 카불에서 다시 만났죠.
and reconnected
as young men in Kabul.
헤로인 판매로 명성을 날릴때 다시 만났단건가요?
Reconnected as he was making
his name in the heroin trade?
전 관여하고 싶지 않았어요
Which I wanted no part of.
전 아메리칸 드림을 쫏아 이 나라로 왔어요
I-I came to this country
to pursue the American dream.
지난 주, 세르게이가 가게에 나타나기 전까진
I've been doing just that
for years,
몇년 간 잘해왔구요
until Sergei walked
into my shop last week.
놀랐겠군요.
느낌이 좋진 않았죠.
Had to be a surprise.
Not a happy one.
우리가 해군과 계약했단 걸 알고 있었고,
He knew we had been contracted
by the Navy
그걸 반입하도록 도와야 한다고 주장했어요
and insisted I help him
deliver a package.
그거요?
A package?
그가 협박한 겁니다.
His threat to my family
was clear.
전 거절할 수 없었구요.
I could not say no.
그걸 스피커안에 장치하면서,
He placed it inside a speaker
아들과 난 안전할 거라 보장하더군요.
and assured me
my son would be safe.
아드님은 어땠나요?
How'd your son feel about it?
그애에겐 말할 수 없었습니다.
MR. BOULOS:
I could not tell him.
내 거짓말 때문에 아들은 죽을 뻔 했다구요.
And my deceit
nearly cost his life.
다행이라고 말씀드리진 못하겠네요.
Someone else wasn't so Luc.
좋습니다.
TONY:
Okay.
세르게이는 지금 어디 있습니까?
Where do we find him?
전 정말 모릅니다.
I wish I knew.
오늘 만났을 땐, 죽여버리고 싶었어요
When I saw him today,
I wanted to kill him myself.
세르게이를 만난거군.
He saw Sergei?
오늘 만났다구요?
You saw him today?
대담하게도 전활 했더군요.
He had the nerve to call,
내 아들을 걱정하는 척하면서,
pretending to be
concerned for my son,
장치를 요구했어요.
then demanding a device.
무슨 장치요?
저도 사용허가를 받아서
What kind of device?
I keep only one in stock
딱 한대만 갖고 있던 건데..
for the proper
authorities to use.
핸드폰의 수신을 방해하는 송신기 입니다.
It's a transmitter that blocks
cell-tower reception.
핸드폰 교란기
BISHOP:
A cell-phone jammer.
휴대 가능하고, 범위도 넓어서,
MR. BOULOS: It's portable, long-range,
(dialing)
매우 비싼 장치죠.
very expensive.
(line ringing)
그자가 가져갔어요.
And he just took it.
깁스, 제발 받아요..
Come on, Gibbs, pick up.
세르게이.
Sergei.
깁스가 아니라,
Not Gibbs...
특수요원 포넬 아니신가, 맞나?
but Special Agent Fornell,
is it?
서로 인사한 적은 없었지 아마..
We've yet to be
formally introduced.
난 잘알지.
I know you...
이 개같은 자식..
you murdering son of a bitch.
그래.
Yes.
실례하지.
My apologies.
난 자네말고 깁스를 잡으러 온거거든.
I meant only to hurt Gibbs.
딸을 생각한다면, 허튼 짓은 하지마..
Never realizing how much
Miss Sterling got around.
깁스는 어딨나?
Where is he?
난들 알겠나..
Like I'd ever tell you.
내가 자네 아내를 죽였는데 말야..
I took the mother of your child.
자네 딸을 고아로 만드는 걸, 망설일것 같나?
Do you think
I'd hesitate
to make that little girl
an orphan altogether?
좋으실데로...
Suit yourself.
(groaning)
(grunting)
러시아의 그 숲으로 되돌아 온건가?
We're back in
the Russian forest?
역사를 고쳐쓰려고, 깁스요원?
Out to rewrite history,
Agent Gibbs?
시간을 되돌리려고?
Turn back the clock?
가능하다면 좋겠는데 말이지.
FORNELL:
If only that were possible.
깁스는 어딨나?
Where is Gibbs?
이건 말야.. 나와 깁스의 문제야, 넌 빠져.
This is between...
me and him, and no one else.
이젠 너와 나의 문제다, 세르게이.
This is between you
and me now, Sergei.
깁스가 내 가족에게 뭔짓을 했는지,
Perhaps you don't know,
Agent Fornell,
잘 모르는거 같은데, 포넬 요원..
what Gibbs took from me.
아, 니 가족에 대해서라면 나도 잘알지.
Oh, I know all about
your family tree.
근데, 나도 가족이란게 있어.
But I have a family, too.
이건 다이앤을 위해서다.
This is for Diane.
이거?
And this?
이게 뭔데?
What is this?
뭔데?
What?
내가 보기엔 말야, 너한테 몇가지 선택지가 있어.
Well, it seems to me
that you have some options.
무기를 버리고, 팔을 올려서 항복하던가...
You could drop
that sidearm,
raise your arms
and surrender...
그건 내 스타일이 아니지..
Not exactly my style.
그렇지.
No.
아니면, 내가 쏠 수 있도록 열심히 도망치던가..
Or you could run,
make us hunt you down.
어떤 기분인지, 함 해보자구..
See what that feels like.
(click)
내가 잡았어.
FORNELL:
I got him.
그래..
Yeah.
기분이 좀 나아졌나?
You feel better?
전혀..
Not even close.
모, 조금쯤은..
Well, maybe a little.
깁스..
Gibbs.
방금 디노조와 맥기에게 보고받았는데,
I just heard
from DiNozzo and McGee.
미쉬노프가 아직도 죽어있답니다.
Mishnev is still dead.
그걸 농담이라고 하나, 레온?
That supposed to be
a joke, Leon?
전에 그 자가 우릴 조롱했었죠.
He fooled us before.
이번엔 못할거야.
Not this time.
확실할겁니다.
That's for sure.
이봐, 나 정말 기분이 더럽다네..
Man, I really do look like hell.
자넬 속였다고 생각하나, 투바이어스?
Did you think we were
lying to you, Tobias?
뜨거운 물로 샤워해도 나아지지 않을 만큼, 별거 아닐겁니다.
Well, it's nothing
a hot shower can't fix.
동감입니다, 레온.
Amen to that, Leon.
딸아이랑 좋은 음식을 먹어야겠네요
And a hot meal
with my daughter.
그럼, 아주 좋은 타이밍이네요
Well, then,
our timing's perfect.
초밥보단 더 괜찮은거 사주실거죠?
And I was thinking
more of sushi?
뭐든지 사주마, 아가.
FORNELL:
Whatever you want, baby.
뭐든, 다 해줄께..
Whatever you need, it's yours.
자, 그럼..
Well, then...
먼저 갑니다..
Good night.
잘가게.
잘가세요.
Good night.
뭐 더 필요한 일 없으시면 저도..
And unless you need
anything else,
제이크가 기다려서요..
Jake is waiting for me.
둘이 할 얘기가 참 많겠네요..
We have much to discuss.
살살해..
Go easy on him.
안녕히계세요.
Good night.
뭔가, 레온?
What, Leon?
아뇨..
Nothing.
제가 더 알아야 할건 없나해서..
Unless there's something
I should know.
제가 알아야 할게 있으면,
Some detail I missed
말해주실 거라 믿습니다.
you might need to tell me.
수고하세요, 깁스.
Good night, Gibbs.
잘가게.
Night.
(knock at door)
네, 열렸습니다. 들어와요.
Yeah, it's open.
Come on in.
(door opens)
열려있군요.
Open.
왜 놀랍지 않을까요?
Why am I not surprised?
어서와요, 안톤.
Hello, Anton.
보드카는 없고, 차가운 맥주는 있습니다.
Don't have any vodka,
but there's a cold beer
in the fridge.
꽤나 배려하셨군요....
You are considerate...
오래있진 않을 겁니다..
but I cannot stay.
다행히 이번 일은 성공했습니다
I understand
we had some success.
그렇게 말할 수 있겠죠.
You could say that.
제가 침착하지 못했단건 인정합니다.
I admit I was nervous.
처음엔 그도 꽤 의심하더군요,
He was quite
suspicious at first,
근데, 당신이 맞았어요..
but you were right.
당신이 넬리 배닌을 죽인게 계략이라고 하니까,
When I told him you killing
Nelly Benin was a fake,
입질하더군요.
he bought it--
당신이 그를 낚아보자구.. 한것처럼.
as you say--
hook, line and sinker.
사람들은 믿고싶은 것만 믿는 법이죠
People believe what
they want to believe.
Had he not,
그가 믿지 않았다면,
여기서 이런 대화를 나눌 수 없을겁니다.
we might not be having
this conversation right now.
어쨌든 성공했군요.
But here we are.
(speaks Russian)
참사관님..그럼.
Counselor.
감사합니다.
Thank you.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
메인 악역이 이렇게 쉽게 죽다니.. 대체 시즌 12는 어디로 가는 걸까요?..
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man